## **ASHWIN BHAT**

abhat4@jhu.edu \* 305-878-1762 \* linkedin.com/in/abhat4 \* theshwin.com

### **ABOUT**

I am currently a senior, majoring in computer engineering with minors in robotics, computer science, and applied math/statistics. I am primarily interested in opportunities in engineering to gain experience with real-world applications. I enjoy working with robots and computers and conducting research. From my previous work, I have learned how to tackle challenging problems and find solutions to them.

### **EDUCATION**

### Johns Hopkins University

August 2014-May 2018

#### Whiting School of Engineering

Major: Computer Engineering; Minors: Robotics, Applied Math and Statistics, and Computer Science Cumulative GPA: 3.21, Upper-Division GPA: 3.43; Dean's List: Fall 2016, Spring 2018

- Robotics Club
- Institute of Electrical & Electronics Engineers (Vice President)
- Association for Computing Machinery

### John A. Ferguson Senior High School

August 2010-June 2014

### International Baccalaureate Diploma Program, GPA: 4.000, 8.033 (weighted)

- Top 1% of class of 1050 students and Summa Cum Laude.
- Earned the IB Diploma and AP Scholar with Distinction. President of STEM club, Vice President of Math Honor Society.

### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** 

Programming Skills Engineering Skills Selected Coursework

Other Skills

C/C++, Python, Matlab, VHDL, C#, Java, HTML & CSS

Robot OS (ROS), OpenCV, PyTorch, scikit-learn, Version Control (Mercurial, Git), Machine Learning

FPGA Synthesis (VHDL), Arduino (Uno, Due, etc.), PCB Design (Eagle), LTSpice, Electronics Lab equipment, Soldering Computer Vision, FPGA Lab, Robot Sensors/Actuators, ML: Deep Learning, Algorithms for Robotics, Electronics/Circuits Research (scientific/engineering), Technical and Creative writing/Proposal writing, Presentation, Teamwork, Carpentry

### **EXPERIENCE**

# JHU Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics: Autonomous Systems, Control, and Optimization Lab

September 2016-May 2018

### Undergraduate Research Assistant

- Installed newer components including flight control systems, guidance, and computers on drones for motion/planning research.
- Researched and implemented motion-based teleoperation for a robotic arm attached to a drone for use in object manipulation.
- Implemented first person view teleoperation for aerial object manipulation.

# Florida International University: School of Computing and Information Science

May 2017-August 2017

### Undergraduate Research Assistant at NSF/DoD Funded Research Experience for Undergraduates (REU)

- Applied advanced statistical techniques such as principal component analysis to improve hyper parameter selection for use in augmented terrain-based navigation by robots.
- Developed a method for assigning weights to water parameters while reducing correlation.
- Used these selection and weighting techniques to develop an algorithm for reducing autocorrelation to create combined parameter data maps for underwater localization.

### PROJECTS – more details and links to repositories/papers on my website (theshwin.com)

### **Computer Vision Projects**

- 1) Augmented Webcam Experience
- 2) Face matching

### **Robot Sensors/Actuators**

Bluetooth-controlled, obstacle-avoiding car

### FPGA Synthesis Lab

Logic Analyzer/Frequency Meter

- 1) Developed an augmented webcam experience using finger and face detection/tracking and implemented face filters/overlays depending on gestures in the video feed in real-time.
- 2) Implemented Siamese networks to recognize facial similarity between pairs of faces using PyTorch.

Built a small robotic car that used ultrasonic sensors to detect and avoid obstacles. Implemented a bluetooth module and programmed bluetooth control of the car to have autonomous and manual modes.

Implemented an FPGA-based logic analyzer that could be used as a USB oscilloscope/picoscope. Implemented a frequency meter that counted the frequency of inputted signals.